Aaron Rumery

Senior Software Engineer

Manchester, NH | +1.603.631.6284 | hello@aaronrumery.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

Forward-Thinking Senior Software Engineer showcasing over ten years of developing innovative technologies to improve user experiences and resolve complex problems. Strategic, influential leader experienced in co-authoring specifications, design documents, documentation, and other training and educational content. Committed to serving as a versatile, collaborative, and enthusiastic team leader with a passion for tackling challenges across the full stack.

Career Highlights

- ★ Developed fault-tolerant data pipelines to reduce downtime and increase data throughput.
- ★ Increased inventory placement speed tenfold and enhanced user engagement metrics through Elixir and Erlang/OTP.
- ★ Partnered with diverse teams at Cars.com to gather requirements and find a balance between user experience, architecture, and functionality.

Core Competencies

Amazon Web Services | Coding | Design Reviews | Code Review | Feedback | Style Guidelines | Documentation |
Educational Content | Product Updates | User Feedback | Triage Issues | Service Operations | Quality Assurance |
Product Development | Stakeholder Management | Architectural Design | Scalability | Performance Optimization |
Mentoring | Leadership & Collaboration | Version Control | Continuous Integration | Deployment Automation

Professional Experience

Kraken Digital Assets Exchange | Remote

2021 - 2024

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Reduced downtime 2% and increased data throughput 11% by engineering fault-tolerant data pipelines through Rust, Golang, and TypeScript.
- Cut message processing latency by optimizing Kafka-based data ingestion and processing to ensure 99.9% data delivery reliability.
- Decreased operational costs 5% and improved scalability by architecting AWS infrastructure that supported data-intensive applications with 99.99% uptime.
- Developed analytics frameworks to enhance actionable insights extraction efficiency, drive data-driven decision-making, and improve product performance.
- Reduced bugs and improved code maintainability in Node.js projects by leading TypeScript adoption to accelerate feature delivery.
- Delivered resource savings by developing and implementing automation strategies to reduce manual intervention and improve workflow efficiency.
- Improved code coverage metrics 17% and increased team productivity by fostering a culture of continuous improvement among junior engineers.
- Increased employee satisfaction by cultivating an inclusive environment and advocating for team cohesion and innovation.

Cars.com | Remote 2017 - 2021

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER: 2019 – 2021 SOFTWARE ENGINEER: 2017 – 2019

- Promoted to Senior Software Engineer by delivering exceptional results and demonstrating leadership potential.
- Accelerated inventory placement tenfold with Elixir and Erlang/OTP, leveraging GenStage, Flow, and streaming technologies.
- Increased user engagement metrics by implementing the Elixir Phoenix Framework to improve user experience and functionality across multiple dimensions of the Cars.com website.
- Reduced costs 3% and improved user satisfaction by engineering a greenfield dealer management system, automating dealership and inventory data on our platform.
- Enhanced search speed and precision 30%, improving customer retention 6%, by deploying advanced search functionality powered by Elasticsearch and Redis.

- Decreased data discrepancies by integrating APIs from various third-party vendors.
- Achieved a balance between user experience, architecture, and functionality by facilitating collaboration with cross-functional non-technical teams to gather requirements.

Reduced post-launch issue resolution time as a co-author for specifications, design documents, and

documentation.

MVPindex | Dallas, TX 2017

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Reduced processing times 15% using Node.js, Kafka, SQL, Elasticsearch, and AWS.
- Improved audience segmentation by collaborating with data scientists on Facebook data to develop advanced demographic models.
- Increased user acquisition and retention by integrating OAuth for multiple social media logins.

ZEFR | PROVO, UT 2015 – 2017

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Boosted collaboration among internal marketing teams and external partners by developing and deploying an Influencer Management System (IMS).
- Enhanced campaign insights by designing and implementing data extraction and analysis procedures to monitor daily social media posts from top influencers.
- Increased campaign engagement 35% and reduced acquisition costs 10% by enhancing influencer discovery and targeting precision in ad campaigns with advanced faceted search features.

Previous Roles:

Web Developer at About Time Technologies, LLC: 2014 – 2015

Technical Supervisor at Bluehost: 2012 – 2014

Education

Extended Studies Machine Learning Engineering Bootcamp

UC San Diego, Online: Anticipated 2024

• **Relevant Coursework**: Deep Learning, Computer Vision and Image Processing, The Machine Learning Engineering Stack, ML Models at Scale and In Production, Deploying ML Systems

Certificate Of Completion, Full Stack Software Engineer

DevMountain, Provo, UT: 2015

• **Relevant Coursework**: HTML 5 & CSS3, JavaScript, Git & GitHub, jQuery, AngularJS, Test-Driven Development, Node.JS, Databases

Coursework toward a Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.) In Computer Science

Utah Valley University, Orem, UT: 2011 - 2012

Technology & Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Rust, Golang, TypeScript, Node.js, Elixir, Python

Frontend Development: HTML, CSS, React, Angular

Backend Development: Express, Koa, NextJS, Apollo Server, Phoenix, Rocket **Data Engineering:** Kafka, Airflow, Spark, Broadway, Bull, Oban, Rayon, Tokio

Databases: Elasticsearch, Solr, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MariaDB, ScyllaDB, Redis,

MongoDB, DynamoDB

Development Tools: Git, GitLab CI/CD, GitHub Actions, CircleCI, AWS CodePipeline, Docker,

Kubernetes, Nomad

Software Testing: Unit testing, property-based testing, integration testing, Mocha, Jest, Chai,

ExUnit, PhantomJS, Puppeteer, Selenium

Cloud Technologies: AWS **Development Methodologies:** Agile